<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tech Notes</title><link href="http://xiaojianfeng.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://xiaojianfeng.github.io/feeds/clinical.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://xiaojianfeng.github.io/</id><updated>2016-02-01T19:30:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Males Contribute More Mutations Than Females</title><link href="http://xiaojianfeng.github.io/clinical/males-contribute-more-mutations-than-females.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-01T19:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Xiao Jianfeng</name></author><id>tag:xiaojianfeng.github.io,2016-02-01:clinical/males-contribute-more-mutations-than-females.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A good explanation from http://users.rcn.com/jkimball.ma.ultranet/BiologyPages/M/Mutations.html#Males_Contribute_More_Mutations_Than_Females.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;If most mutations occur during S phase of cell division, then males should be more at risk. This is because

* only two dozen (24) or so mitotic divisions occur from the fertilized egg that starts a little girl&amp;#39;s embryonic development and the setting aside of her future eggs (which is done long before she is even born).
* The sperm of a 30-year old man, in contrast, are the descendants of at least 400 mitotic divisions since the fertilized egg that formed him.

So,

* fathers are more likely than mothers to transmit newly-formed mutations to their children.
    - The sperm of a 25-year-old man might carry some 45 new mutations. This number rises at a rate of about 1 per year, so the sperm of a 40-year-old man may transmit some 60 new mutations to his children (about 20 of these in coding regions).
    - No matter what the age of the mother, she transmits only about 15 new mutations to her offspring. (But chromosomal aberrations, like aneuploidy, are more apt to arise in eggs than in sperm, and the incidence of these increases with maternal age.)
* These data explain why the children of aged fathers suffer more genetic disorders than those of young fathers.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;翻译如下：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;假如大部分的突变都发生在细胞分裂的S期，那么男性产生突变的概率更高，因为：

* 女性从受精卵的胚胎发育开始，到卵子的形成（在女性出生之前很久就已经形成），只经历了大概24次有丝分裂。

* 与此相对，一个30岁男性的精子，是发育成该男性的受精卵经过至少400次有丝分裂的后代。

所以，

* 父亲比母亲更容易遗传新发的突变给子女。

    - 一个25岁男子的精子可能携带大概45个新发突变，这个数字大概每年增加1，一个40岁男子的精子可能遗传60个新发突变给其子女（这其中有大约20突变位于编码区）。

    - 不论母亲的年龄大小，其遗传给后代的突变数目大概是15个。但是染色体异常--比如多倍体--在卵子中产生的概率比在镜子中更高，并且此概率随着母亲年龄增加而增加。

* 这些数据解释了为什么年老父亲的孩子患遗传病的概率比年轻父亲的孩子要高。
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="mutation"></category></entry><entry><title>exome sequencing for newborn screening</title><link href="http://xiaojianfeng.github.io/clinical/exome-sequencing-for-newborn-screening.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-25T23:22:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Xiao Jianfeng</name></author><id>tag:xiaojianfeng.github.io,2015-06-25:clinical/exome-sequencing-for-newborn-screening.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天看到一个消息，美国一家叫做Baby Genes的公司准备推广运用全外显子组测序进行新生儿筛查。我觉得这是一个大趋势:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;外显子测序越来越便宜，现在外显子组测序成本大概四千人民币，再过几年假如价格再降一些，大家也更有钱一些，价格就越来越不是问题了。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;外显子组数据分析，包括方法和临床表型与基因型关联信息的数据集的进步，使得外显子组测序变得越来越容易，门槛越来越低&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;外显子组测序能一次性解读绝大部分的遗传病（有一些遗传病还没有找到相关基因，还有一些遗传病的相关的区域不在外显子区域）
拭目以待。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;另外，复旦儿童医院在2015年的中华询证儿科杂志（？）上发表了一系列的介绍外显子测序临床应用的文章，值得一读。&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>